Once we gather sensor data about the car's surroundings and its movement,
بمجرد أن نجمع بيانات الاستشعار حول كماليات السيارة وحركتها،
we can then use this information to improve our initial location prediction.
يمكننا بعدها أن نستخدم هذه المعلومات لتحسين التنبؤ المبدئي بالموقع.
For example, say we sense lane markers and specific terrain, and we say, hmm.
مثلًا، إذا قلنا أننا نستشعر محدِّد حارات السير وتضريس معين في الطريق، وفكَّرنا قليلًا.
Actually, we know from
في الواقع، نعلم
previously collected data that if we sense landlines close to the sides of the car,
من البيانات التي سبق جمعها أننا إذا استشعرنا خطوط هواتف أرضية قريبة من جوانب السيارة
the car is probably located in the center of the lane.
فيُحتمل أن تقع السيارة في منتصف حارة السير.
We also know that if we sense that our tires are pointing to the right,
نعلم أيضًا أننا إذا استشعرنا أن إطارات سيارتنا تشير إلى اتجاه اليمين
we're probably on a curved section of the road.
فيُحتمل أننا على جزء منحنٍ من الطريق.
So this sensor data,
إذًا بيانات الاستشعار هذه،
combined with what we already know about the road and the car,
إلى جانب ما نعلمه بالفعل عن الطريق والسيارة،
gives us more information about where our location is most likely to be.
يمنحوننا مزيد من المعلومات حول الموقع الأكثر احتمالية لوجودنا.
So using the sensor information,
إذًا باستخدام معلومات الاستشعار،
we can improve our initial prediction and better estimate our car's location.
يمكننا تحسين تنبؤنا المبدئي ونخمِّن موقع سيارتنا بشكل أفضل.
Bayes rule gives us a mathematical way to correct our measurements,
تقدم لنا قاعدة Bayes طريقة رياضية لتصحيح قياساتنا،
and let's us move from an uncertain prior belief to something more and more probable.
وتسمح لنا بالانتقال من اعتقاد مسبق غير مؤكد إلى شيء أكثر احتمالية بكثير.
You'll see Bayes rule come up again and again in robotics.
سوف ترون أن قاعدة Bayes تظهر مرارًا وتكرارًا في الروبوتات.
And in this lesson, you'll gain a greater understanding of Bayes rule.
وفي هذا الدرس، ستكتسبون فهمًا أعظم لقاعدة Bayes.